Accessibility Notes

Regardless of any digital rights management or the license terms a digital book is released under, libraries and educational facilities and probably some other institutions have the legal right—and perhaps legal obligation in some cases—to modify digital books to reduce or eliminate accessibility barriers for their users that need them mitigated. Legalities aside, when a digital publication can be modified to mitigate or reduce an accessibility barrier it certainly is the moral thing to do.

To help facilitate this, every page in the ePub spine references the file css/a11y.css as the last style sheet that is referenced so that any accessibility fixes that can be made with CSS can be placed in that file and they will always override any default styles defined by the ePub viewer or any CSS definitions defined in this ePub that may be causing accessibility issues for a user. Modification of that file does require some technical skill.

It is the explicit goal of Pipfrosch Press for everything we publish to meet the WCAG 2.1 ‘AA’ conformance level and it is the desire of Pipfrosch Press to meet as many ‘AAA’ success criteria as practical within the current funding limitations.

Not all accessibility barriers have corresponding WCAG 2.1 success criterion. When aware of such barriers, Pipfrosch Press generally considers them to be ‘AAA’ issues which means we try to provide solutions when practical to do so within the current funding limitations but may not always be able to.

Known WCAG Conformance Issues

WCAG ‘A’ conformance issues

Hopefully none exist.

WCAG ‘AA’ conformance issues

Visual Technical Nomenclature Terms

WCAG ‘AAA’ conformance issues

Contrast Issue
Italicized Text Issue
Figure Font Size
Phonetic Markup
‘Æ’ and ‘Œ’ Ligatures
High Contrast Text

Visual Technical Nomenclature Terms

Some technical terms used in this ePub—such as mammalian dentition notation—has a visual aspect to the nomenclature.

Assistive technology for the print disabled may not present those terms to users in an optimal way without proper tagging instructing the assistive technology in how to present the terms to the user. With mathematical equations, MathSpeak can be used to solve this issue but I am currently ignorant on what the proper methods are for visual presentations of terms that are not mathematics.

I was not able to find the specific WCAG success criterion this violates but Pipfrosch Press considers this to be a level ‘AA’ conformance issue. This ePub is intended to convey scientific information which makes proper markup of technical terms that have a visual component critical. This must be solved before the initial official release of this ePub.

Contrast Issue

The covers for the original ‘Numbers’ in Volume 1 had a greenish background color behind the artwork and text. For nostalgia reasons I have attempted to emulate those covers including a greenish background color.

The background color I chose has a 7.73:1 contrast ratio with the ‘not quite but nearly black’ text color and does pass the necessary contrast threshold for WCAG ‘AA’ Success Criterion 1.4.3 at all font sizes but it barely passes ‘AAA’ Success Criterion 1.4.6 and may present issues for the text that uses a smaller than ‘normal’ font size. The font size used on the emulated covers is actually determined by the display screen size, so that may happen.

Contrast Issue Solution

For a user who needs more contrast than the greenish emulated covers provide, add the following to the css/a11y.css file:

.svgcoverbg { fill: none; }

That will remove the purely nostalgic background color from the emulated covers.

Italicized Text Issue

For some users, including but not exclusively many dyslexic users, italicized text can be an access barrier. I am not able to find a specific WCAG success criterion related to italicized text but that does not make this issue any less real.

A web page that does discuss dyslexic accessibility issues: 6 Surprising Bad Practices That Hurt Dyslexic Users.

Italicized Text Solution

To accomodate users who have issues with italicized text, there are already CSS definitions in a file called css/noitalics.css to override most of the uses of italicized text within this ePub but in a visually meaningful way so that the visual cues are not lost.

Copy the contents of that file into the css/a11y.css file and most of the italicized text will be replaced with upright text, with the following exceptions:

The ePub cover is a bitmap image, text on the ePub cover can not be altered with CSS. This is a limitation of ePub and digital books in general. The cover is primarily intended for the digital library and ePub viewers need to turn it into a thumbnail sized for the library view without being expected to rasterize a vector image.
A few technical nomenclature terms—such as the dental notation pm^2—remain italicized.

In the second case, if you really need to override the italics you still can by also adding the following to the css/a11y.css file:

.nomen { font-style: normal; } span.lingual { font-style: normal; }

Figure Font Size

I currently classify this as a ‘AAA’ issue although it may actually be a ‘AA’ issue (Success Criterion 1.4.4 depending upon if the text is considered a caption). I am not able to find a specific ‘AAA’ success criterion for this issue but that does not make it any less real.

When a user needs a larger font size, increasing the font size used by the ePub viewer will not increase the font size used in figures that are drawn with SVG. There is not an easy solution to this problem that I am aware of.

Even though it should be technically possible for an ePub viewer to allow the user to zoom in on a part of a figure as needed, it seems that very few ePub viewers actually implement this kind of functionallity. I have personally only seen it implemented when an SVG image is embedded in an ePub page using the <img/> tag, but that is not how figures are done in this ePub as that method does not seem to allow the image to have access to fonts embedded within the ePub.

I am hopeful that in the near future I will either discover an existing solution to this issue or if one does not yet exist, that a solution will be developed that ePub viewers implement.

Phonetic Markup

This is ‘AAA’ Success Criterion 3.1.6.

The ePub 3.2 specification specifically provides a mechanism for adding phonetic markup to words and phrases that a text to speech synthesiser (TTS) is likely to mispronounce or for which pronunciation may be ambiguous based on the spelling. This ePub is currently woefully inadequate in implementing such markup.

Presently I am not aware of any ePub viewers that actually implement this part of the ePub 3.2 standard but I still want to provide the proper phonetic markup so that if and when a viewer does support it, this ePub will already be properly tagged.

‘Æ’ and ‘Œ’ Ligatures

Journal of Mammalogy Volume 1 made heavy use of the ‘æ’ ligature and some use of the ‘œ’ ligature. These ligatures can cause the same issues for some users that italicized text causes.

It is the opinion of Pipfrosch Press that ePub viewers should have a setting that automatically expands those ligatures but Pipfrosch Press is also aware that having an opinion does not actually mitigate the resulting access barrier for impacted users.

This is not something can be solved with a CSS declaration. A version of this ePub with those ligatures expanded—along with the previously mentioned css/noitalics.css style sheet already applied—will be available from the Pipfrosch Press website.

High Contrast Text

For some users, including many dyslexic users but also others, too much contrast between the text and the background can be an accessibility barrier that increases difficulty in reading and reduces comprehension.

Pipfrosch Press does not define a text color or background color for the main content, doing so would interfere with the operation of ‘night mode’ with some ePub viewers. However it is relatively easy to set.

High Contrast Text Text Solution

The ePub viewer really should allow the user to define the text color and background color but in the event the ePub viewer a users uses does not and the contrast is too high, add the following to the css/a11y.css file:

body { color: #222222; background-color: #ededed; }

That combination of nearly but not quite black on top of a light gray background works very for me, but of course you can adjust the colors as needed.

Donations

I am a strong supporter of the Open Access concepts presented by Aaron Swartz (may he never be forgotten) in his Guerilla Open Access Manifesto, including:

“Only those blinded by greed would refuse to let a friend make a copy. Large corporations, of course, are blinded by greed.”

For some people, even charging $1.00 results in a financial access barrier that prevents access to the resource. Those people are not any less worthy than Jeff Bezos or Mark Zuckerberg. This is why this digital book is provided for free without any charge.

That being said, an incredible amount of time, energy, and even some personal financial resources went into the production of this digital book.

In 1920, $3.50 would have given you a 1 year subscription to the Journal of Mammalogy. In 2020 assuming I did my maths right, that would be the equivalent of about $45.00.

I only ask you for $10.00, split between Pipfrosch Press and the American Society of Mammalogists. You can donate more to either if you would like, of course, or donate less or even donate none. The choice is completely yours to make and depends upon both your financial means and your personal level of generosity.

Pipfrosch Press

At this time, hopefully soon to be remedied, Pipfrosch Press is not a legal entity. Donations can be made to Michael A. Peters with the understanding that such donations are not at this time tax deductible.

Donations will help Pipfrosch Press continue to produce Open Access digital publications, both the republication of previously print published academic content and the production of fresh content.

To donate using the Android or iOS/iPadOS “CashApp” application:

CashApp tag $AliceWonderMisc

To donate using PayPal:

PayPal Payment Address pipfroschpress@gmail.com. Note that PayPal allows you to make it a monthly donation, only check the box for that if that really is your intention.

Thank you.

American Society of Mammalogists

To donate to the American Society of Mammalogists and help their continued production of the Journal of Mammalogy (now in production for over 100 years!) please see their donation page:

https://asm.wildapricot.org/Donate

Please note that Journal of Mammalogy has been an Open Access journal since 1996 and is one of the first journals to embrace the Open Access movement. You can access their Open Access content at https://www.mammalsociety.org/articles. Donations help fund what they make freely available.

Speaking presumably on their behalf, Thank you.

ePub Notes

This digital book is not an attempt to create a perfect digital facsimile of the original work. Rather, it is an attempt to create a representation of the original work that takes full advantage of the ePub technological capabilities in a manner that reduces or eliminates content access barriers for users who have them, which is quite a few of us whether we realize it or not.

The purpose of the original work was to convey meaningful information to an audience that wanted to consume that information. The purpose of this digital book version likewise is to convey that meaningful information but in a manner that expands the audience of those who are able to consume the information using modern technology. To meet that goal, some typographical changes have been made.

General Changes

Journal of Mammalogy Volume 1 was initially distributed in five different Numbers (issues) published at different times during 1919 and 1920.

Volume 1 was later also distributed as a single bound book containing all five Numbers.

The pagination between the separately distributed Numbers and the single bound volume are identical, but there are some difference worth noting:

The separately distributed ‘Numbers’ had a cover that included a Table of Contents on the cover and on the inside of that cover, before the pagination of the ‘Numbers’ began, they had non-academic frontmatter notes about the structure of the American Society of Mammalogists and the Journal of Mammalogy. Later printings of the single bound book, such as what I possess, did not include those covers or the frontmatter that preceded the numbered pages. It appears that earlier printings of the single bound book did in fact contain them.
The single bound book contains an index to content in all five ‘Numbers’ as backmatter. If this index existed in the separately distributed ‘Numbers’ then either it was issue specific in the first four ‘Numbers’ or was only included with ‘Number 5’.

This digital book was created by transcribing the single bound volume that I have, which at one point belonged to Vassar College and appears to have been rebound before I acquired it. To reproduce the plates and figures in the highest possible quality, the book was unbound so that the pages containing the plates and figures could be photographed flat at a very high resolution. I did rebind the volume after this process because I treasure it.

The bound volume that I possess did not contain the individual Number covers or the information printed on the inside of the covers but I was able to obtain the pronghorn image for SVG tracing from the American Society of Mammalogists website and I was able to obtain the inside cover information from a PDF file produced by The Smithsonian Institution, which they created from scans of Volume 1 Numbers in the possession of the Remington Kellogg library of Marine Mammalogy. It is possible there is other content from the original Volume 1 Numbers that was not on numbered pages that is both absent from my bound volume and from the PDF scans provided by the Smithsonian Institution. In the event I find such content exists, it can be added in a future edition of this digital book.

The content from numbered pages I do believe is complete.

In this digital book, I have placed a facsimile of the individual Number covers at the beginning of where content from that particular Number begins, though the facsimile of the covers are intentionally not identical. For example, the Table of Contents has been moved to follow the Number cover rather than being integrated into the cover. For typographical reasons on small screen displays I also left out the notes about second-class postage that were part of the Number covers.

The non-academic notes about the American Society of Mammalogists and the Journal of Mammalogy from the inside front cover of the Numbers but that do not appear in my bound book have been added for the benefit of the historical context, but they are added as backmatter at the end of the Number content rather than as originally presented frontmatter preceding the Number content.

The index from the bound book version of Volume 1 has been preserved but reformatted with how it presents trinomial nomenclature references.

The original publication is typeset for fixed layout printing. This digital book is typeset for responsive layout viewing on a digital screen of unknown dimensions while allowing the user to adjust parameters such as font size and line spacing that impact the rendering of the layout and how many virtual pages are required.

For this reason, photographic plates and tabular data and most drawn figures are placed at the end of the journal article in which they appear. Hyperlinks allow the reader to easily jump to the photographic plate, table, or drawn figure from within the content when it is referenced.

In academic journals, there are many abbreviations that are used that are well understood by scholars within the field of study but provide comprehension barriers to those who are not familiar with those abbreviations and also result in an absolutely horrible experience for users that depend upon on a screen reader to access the content.

Some abbreviations do remain, but many of the abbreviations within the content I expanded to the full meaning to mitigate these access barriers.

Sometimes an academic journal article will indicate a logical section using an italicized word followed by a period followed by an em-dash. In a few cases, this can cause some confusion if the logical section defined that way should have the same logical level as the logical section that precedes it. In those cases, I will split it out as a distinct section heading for the purpose of clarity.

This journal volume often uses four widely spaced periods to indicate an ellipsis, using a non-breaking space between each period. That was fairly common in that temporal era and I believe is the method specified in the Chicago Manual of Style.

I prefer to use an ellipsis glyph (…) in those cases, let the font decide how to render it. An ellipsis glyph makes it easier for machine parsers to understand it is an ellipsis.

I have added a contents navigation list to the beginning of articles where it is beneficial, and also I have indicated the DOI that uniquely identifies the canonical version of the article at the beginning of each article.

The use of small-cap font variants can be problematic in digital books so they are not used within this ePub. In some cases where the journal uses all upper-case characters, I have opted not to for consistent readability.

Typography for print consumption and typography for digital consumption have different considerations that must be taken into account for the best possible reader experience. Thank you for understanding.

Literature Cited Notes

Literature Cited sections and the Recent Literature sections have been altered in the manner in which they present the work.

There are three ‘standard’ styles for citations:

MLA
APA
Chicago

For the most part, the citation method I prefer is very similar to APA with some minor differences.

Some stylistic purists may object to these minor differences. For those purists, they are free to alter their copy of the digital book, no DRM is used.

Most articles within this volume do not actually have a Literature Cited section but instead use full inline references. I do not like full inline references, they tend to break my concentration and reduce my reading comprehension. To mitigate this often over-looked access barrier, I created a unified bibliography that has both the full complete reference and an index to what where it was cited. In place of the full inline reference I usually placed a much shorter inline reference that is a link to the unified bibliography. In a few cases I deemed it appropriate to the context of the article to leave a fuller reference inline. In the very few cases where an article did in fact have its own Literature Cited section, that has been preserved although the hyperlinks within the article still point to the unified bibliography.

Journal and other abbreviations in the bibliography have been fully expanded. The reason for this becomes quite evident if you have ever had to use a screen reader with a bibliography. Whenever I could find a DOI or Handle link for the referenced academic work, I generally added it. The one exception is handle links that point to a Google Books scanned copy where the handle link does not appear to be maintained by the journal. Google Books is very problematic for a variety of reasons, I will not link to them unless the DOI or Handle link that points to a Google Books scanned copy is maintained by the journal that produced the article. When I could not find a DOI or Handle link, I tried to find a URL (preferring BHL) for the resource to link to.

Index Notes

The original index had a few typographical errors that I chose to correct, such as using Myotis ussuriensis where the author used Murina ussuriensis. Both are Bat genera that begin with the letter M, the latter genera only appears once in this volume, easy mistake to make.

However in addition to correcting the minor typographical errors, I made a major structural change worth noting.

With trinomial nomenclature, the original index only listed the reference using genus and subspecies, basically listing the reference the way it would be referenced with binomial nomenclature if the subspecies was elevated to species status.

I am sorry but I find that to be very confusing and counter to the purpose of an index. I went through the index and changed all references to proper full trinomial nomenclature when the author used trinomial nomenclature.

In the 100 years since this volume was first published, some species have undergone a change to the accepted taxonomic nomenclature. Where I am aware of such a change, I added an entry for the currently accepted nomenclature instructing the reader on the synonym used by authors in this volume. This was done primarily for the benefit of young students who may not know to search an index for historic synonyms if they can not find what they are looking for.

Needed Articles

The following articles are wanted for the Supplementary section.

Order of personal importance to me:

Mammalian Dentition
Colorado Wood Rat

Mammalian Dentition

This is desperately needed.

Dentition is frequently used in mammal descriptions and is often a reliable diagnostic for distinguishing similar species or genera. Many of the articles assume the reader has both a basic understanding of mammalian dentition and the terminology used to describe mammalian dentition. Many people however do not.

Describing the terminology is, in my opinion, beyond the scope of the glossary. Definitions should be in the glossary, but there should also be an article that does a better job that the glossary can refer to.

This is, in my opinion, a desperate accessibility need that is needed to help non-biologists get the full value of the journal articles.

The article should be written such that a ‘typical’ high school student can comprehend it.

The article should be written as a stand-alone article that can be reused as needed.

Colorado Wood Rat

Volume 1 Number 5 has an excellent article detailing observations about a wood rat in Colorado that created a home within an abandoned building. I think it would be really fascinating for a naturalist in Colorado who stumbles upon this type of observation to make a modern account of the observation with detailed digital photographs to match the account.

Needed Photographs

The original journal volume contains eighteen black and white photographs.

These photographs were printed on glossy plates, where they experienced some deterioration as the copy of the journal volume in my possession aged, and then they were re-photographed by me for inclusion in this digital book. They are usable but they are not optimal for high-definition digital devices and the aging of the prints has not helped.

It would in my opinion be of benefit to readers if freshly created color images using a digital SLR that show the same concepts portrayed by the original photographs could be provided as supplemental plates. I would prefer it if phone cameras were not used, they probably would produce higher quality images than the current photographs but the images produced are visibly inferior on large displays such as what might be used in a presentation.

If you are a photographer who happens to be in one of the geographical areas needed to recreate fresh versions of these images and are willing to do so, it would be greatly appreciated.

The photographs would need to be released under a license compatible with the Creative Commons BY-SA 4.0 license used for this digital book.

Pipfrosch Press can be contacted at pipfroschpress@gmail.com if you are able to help in this respect.

Order of personal importance to me:

Vertebrate Zoology Museum
Southeastern Washington State
Okefinokee Swamp in Georgia
Great Plains (likely Montana or Wyoming)
Canoga Park, Los Angeles, California
Northwestern Indiana
British Museum, London, England
Colorado

Vertebrate Zoology Museum

Two photographs of a well-preserved California Mastiff Bat (Eumops parotis californicus) are needed to correspond with the photographs in Plate 5 and Plate 6. A dorsal view, and a head view.

Both photographs should have a ruler to indicate size, even though such a ruler is only present in Plate 5. Both photographs must have the museum specimen number as part of the photograph.

Southeastern Washington State

Four photographs are needed to correspond with the photographs in Plate 1 and Plate 2.

These are landscape photos showing four different types of habitat. I have not been to the area but it is my suspicion that suitable opportunities at or very near the same locations still exist, based upon that area being an area chosen by Gray Wolves (Canis lupus occidentalis) expanding from Idaho and Oregon.

Okefinokee Swamp in Georgia

Two photographs are needed to correspond with the photographs in Plate 3.

The first is a landscape photograph from Floyd’s Island Prairie which I believe is only accessible by canoe. As it is a National Wildlife Refuge, I suspect that an opportunity exists to recreate a very similar photograph at the same location. Note that it was photographed in May 1912, the same time of year should probably be chosen.

The second photograph shows a runway of a Round-tailed Muskrat [=Florida Water-Rat] (Neofiber alleni). Assuming the species still persists in the Okefinokee Swamp, ideally the photograph would come from within the Okefinokee Swamp but it is not critical for the photograph to come from within the Okefinokee Swamp as long as the runway is from a Round-tailed Muskrat and is in the same type of habitat.

Great Plains (likely Montana or Wyoming)

Two photographs of Pronghorn (Antilocapra americana) horns are needed to correspond with the photographs in Plate 8, which are from the Yellowstone area.

One is of a new growth horn. This would have to be scavenged from a deceased animal that died in the spring. My guess is that roadkill scavenge would be a likely source.

The second is of a shed horn.

Plate 8 was created by combining two different photographs. I suspect it is possible to recreate the same example using a single photograph with the horns laid out in the same configuration. I also suspect a naturalist living in an area where Pronghorn are plentiful already has suitable horns in a collection that could be photographed.

Canoga Park, Los Angeles, California

A single photograph is needed to correspond with Plate 9.

This is a so-called “portrait” orientation landscape photograph of a bat cave near Owensmouth (modern day Canoga Park).

Fortunately I have been able to identify the location and urban sprawl has not destroyed the habitat where the photograph in Plate 8 was taken. A modern photograph of the same cave would be really nice to have.

The location is the Cave of Munits & Castle Peak in El Escorpión Park.

Northwestern Indiana

A single photograph is needed of a Western Fox Squirrel (Sciurus niger rufiventer) nest to correspond with Plate 7.

In Plate 7, the actual nest was altered removing a side to show the construction of the nest. A stuffed specimen was then posed with the nest.

According to the article, the nests are very well constructed and persist for some time beyond the rearing season. Removal of a wild nest after the rearing season is thus possible with minimal impact to the local population of squirrels, though obviously local laws should be consulted before destruction of an existing nest.

With respect to a stuffed specimen, I suspect a local taxidermy shop would have access to one.

My preference for the re-creation of the scene in Plate 7 would be as part of an educational exhibit at a Natural History Museum rather than just for this digital book.

British Museum, London, England

Two photographs are needed to correspond with the photographs in Plate 4. The need for these photos is in my opinion somewhat superficial but still would be nice to have.

These are photographs of the type specimen for Odocoileus mexicanus, which is mounted antlers in the British Museum. Assuming the British Museum still has the mounted antlers, a photograph from the right side and a photograph from the front would be very good to have. An additional photograph of the nameplate would be nice as well.

Colorado

Four photographs corresponding with the photographs in Plate 10 and Plate 11.

Given the very specific nature of the photographs in relation to the article, I do not believe it would be possible for modern photographs to convey the same meaning.

However I would love to have modern photographs that are similar and are accompabied by an article that matches, much like the photographs in Plate 10 and 11 match the article they accompany.

Glossary of Terms

Many glossary definitions defined here are sourced from Wiktionary.org. If the definition from Wiktionary.org is added to, the date of Wiktionary.org access is appended to the end of the definition.

aestivate
Alternate spelling of estivate
æstivate
Alternate spelling of estivate
anterior premolar
FIXME—Definition term needed.
A. O. U.
Abbreviation for American Ornithologists’ Union—which now goes by the name American Ornithological Society.
basal
1. Basic, elementary; relating to, or forming, the base, or point of origin. 2. (anatomy) Associated with the base of an organism or structure. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
binomial nomenclature
The scientific system of naming each species of organism with a Latinized name in two parts; the first is the genus, and is written with an initial capital letter; the second is some specific epithet that distinguishes the species within the genus. By convention, the whole name is typeset in italics [or is underlined when italics can not be used]. The genus part is often abbreviated to its initial letter e.g. H. sapiens for Homo sapiens. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
calcar
A spur of cartilage that runs from the inner ankle along the outer interfemoral membrane.
cladistics
A commonly used term to refer to phylogenetic systematics.
crepuscular
Active at or around dusk, dawn or twilight. Wiktionary 2020 April 26
distal
Remote from the point of attachment or origin. [Contrast with basal]. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
DOI
An abbreviation for Digital Object Identifier—A persistent unique identifier for a digital object that can be used to resolve the canonical version of a digital object, such as an academic paper.
estivate
To go into stasis or torpor in the summer months. Wiktionary 2020 April 18
fibula
The smaller of the two bones in the lower leg, the calf bone. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
IBIS
Abbreviation of Indian Biodiversity Information System—A ‘a series of web-based, modular and searchable biodiversity portals, designed to compile and present in a comprehensive and scientifically accurate manner the available information on Indian flora and fauna which is readily accessible, free and user-friendly.’ See https://www.indianbiodiversity.org/.
ITIS
Abbreviation of Integrated Taxonomic Information System—A database of taxonomic names including reports on the current consensus regarding the validity of those names. The stated goal of the ITIS “is to create an easily accessible database with reliable information on species names and their hierarchical classification.”
junior synonym
When a taxonomy name is assigned to a type specimen but the type specimen is not actually distinguishable as a distinct taxon from a previously described type specimen, the more recent taxonomy name is considered to be a junior synonym of the previously described taxonomy name and in all but a few very special circumstances—such as the senior name violating a naming convention—the junior synonym is considered invalid.
metatarsus
The part of the foot between the toes and the ankle, especially its five bones. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
nom. nov.
An abbreviation for Nomen Novum—A renaming of a taxon that previously had been assigned a taxonomical name but for which the former name must be invalidated.
nomen nudem
‘Naked Name’—When a new taxonomic name is given but without a type specimen or an adequate description of the type, is considered invalid and referred to as nomen nudem.
patagium
The thin membrane that extends between the limbs and body of a bat or of gliding mammals. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
phylogenetic systematics
Phylogenetic systematics is the formal name for the field within biology that reconstructs evolutionary history and studies the patterns of relationships among organisms. See https://evolution.berkeley.edu/evolibrary/article/phylogenetics_01.
sp. nov.
An abbreviation for Species Nova—A new species that has not previously been assigned a taxonomy binomial nomenclature name.
tarsus
The part of the foot between the tibia and fibula and the metatarsus. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
tibia
The inner and usually the larger of the two bones of the leg or hind limb below the knee, the shinbone. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
tragus
The small piece of thick cartilage of the external ear that is immediately in front of the ear canal. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
type locality
The geographical locality where the specimen used to describe a new species was collected.
uropatagium
The portion of the patagium found between the hind limbs and connecting to the tail. Wiktionary 2020 April 16
vicissitude
A change from one thing to another, in the context of biology this can include taxonomy changes over time.